♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we’ve got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright
on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we’ll
withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there
when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we
will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko
stronger after all ♪
Hey, Ulrich, what are you looking for?
I’m hungry!
You go have breakfast.
There’s something I have to find.
Okay.
I can’t believe this.
(SIGHS)
Eight slices of toast and three bananas.
Not bad, huh?
Hey, are you skipping gym class again?
Yup.
It gives me time to work on
Aelita’s materialization.
What’s wrong?
Afraid the wall’s gonna crumble?
Ha. Very funny.
Can we talk for a second?
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
Hi, Yumi!
Hello.
Hey, look over there. It’s Ulrich.
But…what’s he doing with Sissi?
Hey, Ulrich!
So?
Hey, that’s blackmail.
Why do you expect me to give in to that?
First of all, because it’s hard to say no
to a pretty girl like me.
And second of all,
I’m not going to give you any choice.
(CACKLES)
Come on! Come on!
In the 17th century, all european states
were governed by either a king or a prince.
They ruled over mainly peasant populations.
Hey, what’s going on with them?
I’m seeing things.
Ulrich and SissI? That’s weird.
On the brighter side,
check out how jealous Herb is!
Odd?
Are you listening to me, Odd?
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
We have some important
things to talk about, Sissi.
Come on, hurry up!
Hey! But…
Do you mind explaining?
Okay, here goes.
I’m in a…
I’m in a jam. Big time.
For years I’ve, uh, been keeping a diary.
A what?
A diary!
Sissi found it, and now she’s blackmailing me.
I have to go out with her.
If she thinks she’ll win me over
that way, she’s wrong.
Hold on a second.
In this diary of yours,
did you talk about XANA or Lyoko?
Well, yeah, and if I
don’t do what Sissi says,
she’s gonna tell everybody.
I don’t know what to do.
Don’t worry, Ulrich.
While you’re all at the pool,
Yumi and I will look around.
We’ll find your diary. You’ll see.
The answer is no!
The last time! I did not have a nose job!
So stop asking, huh!
Cut it out, Odd. Leave her alone, will ya?
It’s nothing. I’ll explain.
Take a look, Odd.
Not bad, huh?
This bus is the latest in modern technology.
It’s electricity-driven so it’s
non-polluting, but powerful, too.
Electric and powerful, too, huh?
I’ll bet you this crate
goes about as fast as a snail.
(SINISTER MUSIC)
What the! Huh?
Come on, come on. All aboard, now.
Go sit down, kid.
Okay, what’s the prob?
What is that!
I have no idea!
Sit back down and stay there
until we get to the pool!
Sissi is blackmailing him?
Yeah. Incredible, huh?
What matters now though
is to find Ulrich’s diary
before she starts
blabbing about Lyoko.
I’ll go through her room.
And I’ll call you if I need any help.
I’ll be at the factory.
Good luck.
It’s Jeremie here, Aelita.
Do you copy?
Aelita?
I’m here, Jeremie.
I was waiting for you to call.
In the meantime, I was studying
your world a little more.
There are so many
strange things to discover.
Odd, what’s up? Huh?
Something strange?
What bus?
Isn’t this nice and cozy?
We’re zipping along at two miles an hour.
I don’t believe this!
I got it floored, and it just refuses to move!
Okay, I’ll launch a scan on Lyoko.
I’ll call you if I find something.
Okay. Got you.
Aha.
Bingo.
Oh, no.
This is not Ulrich’s handwriting.
Oh, wow! It’s Sissi’s!
“I’m tired of his acting
as if I don’t even exist.
“I can’t stand watching him
pay so much attention to Yumi…”
So, while he was in the lunchroom,
I went looking around.
I just wanted a picture of him,
but I found much better than that.
Now, he can’t possibly turn me down.
I know what I’m doing isn’t very nice,
but it’s the only way I can
get him to stop ignoring me.
Of all the nasty tricks.
Yumi, did you find Ulrich’s diary?
No, but guess what. I found Sissi’s.
You were right. She knows about Lyoko.
She doesn’t really understand what it is,
but she’s ready to use what she knows.
Rats. Look, you’ve got to find Ulrich’s diary before they come back from the pool.
Don’t worry. I know how to get hold of it.
Hey, what if I ask my father
if we can go to a movie tonight?
That’d be cool, huh?
Huh?
Huh!?
I’m being nice to you right now,
but if you keep ignoring me,
it just might not last, you hear?
A little friendly advice--
pay attention to me,
or the whole school’s gonna read your diary.
Okay, okay. You don’t have to threaten me.
I know exactly what I’m risking.
Oh, yeah?
You really think so, Ulrich?
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
Oh, Yumi.
What do you want?
Well, uh, I wanted to tell you
how much I like your style.
“I ran into that dipstick Jim today!
"What an idiot he looks like
}in that sweaty gym suit of his!”
Okay, okay! What do you want?
Tell me where you’ve got
Ulrich’s diary hidden.
And hurry up,
or all your nasty little secrets
will be on page one of the school paper.
Okay, okay!
If you go into the girl’s bathroom,
it’s in the third stall on the
top of the water tank, you got that?
Okay, I’ll go and check.
Wait! What about my diary!
What…
Thanks a lot, Yumi!
There, you see?
It’s good to have real friends, isn’t it?
It’s about time.
I thought that guy
would never get off your back.
If you know what’s good for you, shut up!
Yumi, what are you doing there?
Nothing, sir!
I felt sick, but I’m fine now!
Aelita?
Jeremie, Odd and Ulrich were right.
XANA’s at it again.
The pulsations are getting stronger.
Aelita, the activated tower is in the desert.
I’m off.
What’s going on now? This is weird!
(SCREAMING)
Hey, get back to your seats!
You’re not allowed to get up!
What’s going on with this bus?
That, kid, I wish I knew!
All I know is it’s out of control!
Hey, it seemed to be working okay
before you recharged the batteries, right?
Yeah, everything was just fine.
But now I can’t…
Ulrich, what’s happening, huh?
We’re in trouble.
XANA has taken complete control of the bus.
Okay. Give me a sec.
I wonder what XANA’s trying to do.
Where are you?
At the corner of Washington Street
and Franklin Avenue.
I’ll call you back
as soon as I can localize you.
We’re in for a rough ride.
Aelita’s gonna need a hand on Lyoko.
We’ve got to go.
Then you go.
I’ll stay here.
(GRUNTING)
Take off your backpacks
and use them as airbags!
Yumi, things are getting tough here.
Come straight to the factory after class.
Right.
Now hurry up and get your
seat belts fastened!
Come on, kid, take it easy.
Just calm down, huh?
Does the little girl need any help?
No thanks.
The little girl can take care of herself.
We’ve just gone through
the Constellation intersection, okay?
Don’t worry, Ulrich.
I’ve got you spotted now.
But I still don’t understand
what XANA is trying to do.
I can see it, Jeremie.
I’ve got a virtual image of the activated tower.
Well done, Aelita.
Stay where you are. Yumi is on her way.
Hurry in the scan!
The situation is getting worse!
Transfer Yumi.
Scanner.
Virtualization.
Yumi! Yumi!
Crazy!
Ulrich, XANA is launching the bus
on the petrochemical complex!
He’s what?
How’s that!
There’s no way to stop this infernal thing!
We don’t have any choice. We have to jump.
Now look what you’ve done, huh!
By cutting the cables, you blocked the door!
Jim, Jeremie thinks we’re headed
straight for the petrochemical plant.
You mind telling me how he knows that?
Uh…we’ll tell you that later,
but for now you just have to trust him.
He can help us.
Okay, okay.
Uh, Ulrich…
Well, I’m really sorry about your diary.
It was wrong to take it.
Please forgive me.
Can I help in any way?
Here. Take this.
You can be the go-between
for Jeremie and me.
Yumi, Aelita, the tower is real close now.
No, wait. This is too easy.
Coming all this way
without seeing even one monster?
There’s got to be a trap.
A sandstorm!
It’s a tornado!
Jeremie, we’ve got a problem here.
Make that two.
There’s a monster behind you!
Calling all cars.
All cars, I said. Calling all cars.
In 10 seconds, the bus should bear left.
He says we’re gonna turn left.
Everybody over here with me.
Maybe we should jump off the bus.
W-What do you think?
It might just be the best idea.
That way at least we won’t go
crashing into the petrochemical plant.
At that speed,
there’s no way we could survive.
Give me that.
Jeremie, how are things going back at Lyoko?
Aelita and Yumi are almost at the tower,
except that they’re caught in a sandstorm.
Okay, we’ll wait a little longer.
Yumi, be careful at the ridge.
If Aelita falls into the digital sea,
she’ll be lost forever.
Yumi! Careful in front of you!
It’s a megatank!
Get up! Hurry!
Whoa!
XANA set a trap for us.
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
Good work, Aelita!
Odd, hurry to the scan.
You’ll be reaching the complex in 10 minutes.
Careful! You’re gonna turn left again.
Everyone to the right!
Yumi!
Hide, Aelita!
And don’t move until Odd
is there with you, understand!
Transfer Odd.
Scanner.
Virtualization.
Aelita!
Hey, Aelita!
Welcome to our world!
Hey, Odd! Odd!
Okay, let’s go to work, Aelita.
Thank you, Odd.
Listen, we only have four minutes left
before we get to the complex.
How are things going on Lyoko?
Okay. Aelita and Odd are handling it.
Careful, there’s a ridge!
Huh?
I have an idea. Follow me.
Odd, you’re out of your mind!
Hurry up now, Aelita!
What’s the matter?
Don’t you like it here, Jim?
Oh, no! We’re gonna crash!
It’s all over for us.
It’s too late.
Well, it was close.
But we did it!
Now, are you ready to go back in time?
Huh?
Here. I didn’t read it.
I swear, Ulrich.
I’ll tell you about it one day, Yumi.
I’d really like that.
I’d better go.
I wouldn’t want to miss Sissi.
Sissi, were you waiting for me?
Looking for something?
Uh…no!
I, uh, I was just passing by, so…
Yes!
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO